Curriculum Vitæ

STEPHANIE STROKA

Contact & Personal Data

Address Neunbrunnenstrasse 33

8050 Zürich

Switzerland

Phone +41 792662664

E-Mail stephanie.stroka@digitalid.net

Citizenship German



Short Summary

I have spent my last years gathering knowledge and experience in different fields of Computer Science: Semantic Web, Computational Systems as well as Security and Software Engineering.

My first work experience was in research and development of Semantic Web technologies with a focus on how to enable a security, identity and permission system.

While finishing my studies at university, I got interested in Computational Engineering. I analyzed the runtime behavior of computational systems with regards of execution time and memory consumption. For my master's thesis, I developed and analyzed a memory allocator for C, which, given a notion of time, automatically deallocates short-living objects on the heap.

Between 2012 and the end of 2015, I was the lead developer of the authentication middleware nevisAuth at AdNovum. We developed solutions for identity federation, API authorization, two-factorand context-based-authentication.

I became curious about entrepreneurship in 2014 and finally joined Synacts in 2016 as a co-founder. At Synacts we built and promoted the Digital ID protocol (https://www.digitalid.net), which is an alternative to the current web protocol HTTP. Digital ID consists of an identity layer, which enables cross-platform authentication and authorization, and a look-up layer, which enables automatic cross-platform synchronization of personal data and files.

Education

University Salzburg

Period September 2009 - 2012

Faculty/Branch Computer Sciences/Applied Informatics

Degree Dipl.-Ing. (equiv. M.Sc.)
Field of Research Computational Systems

Master Thesis Short-term Regions - A Region-based Short-term Memory Allocator

University of Applied Sciences Salzburg

Period September 2005 - June 2009

Branch Information Technology & Systems Management

Degree Dipl.-Ing. (FH)

Diploma Thesis Transaction Management & Historiography in Social Semantic Web

Applications

Final Examination Passed with distinction

International Experience

Denmark

Period August 2009

Activity Worked at University of Aalborg (Funded Exchange Program)

Sweden

Period September 2006 - March 2007

Activity Studied abroad at the University of Halmstad

Work Experience

Synacts GmbH

Period January 2016 - present

Position Software Engineer & Chief Product Officer

Description At Synacts we built products on top of the the Digital ID protocol,

which allows users to prove their identity towards services using cryptographic signatures and look up attributes of others in a decentralized manner. As one of two engineers, I am contributing to the development of the Digital ID library. Furthermore, I was responsible for developing our products - the Digital ID Wallet, Transaction Gateway, Validation Provider, our decentralized file-sharing system and our mobile address

book.

Liure Media UG

Period August 2014 - November 2015
Position Co-founder & Technical Lead

Description Liure Media UG was the startup behind UNTOLD, the web-publisher

of interactive, digital stories and reportages, selected and funded by readers. As a co-founder and technical lead I was responsible for product development, which involved building a scalable, flexible backend for content creation and content management which has two main attributes: Fast creation and deployment of interactive content and fast

delivery of multi-media-heavy stories.

AdNovum Informatik

Period March 2012 - December 2015

Position Software Engineer & Lead Developer

Field of Engineering Web Application Security & Authentication Systems

Description I lead the development of nevisAuth - an authentication middleware,

which is part of the access control and identity management solution of AdNovum. As a lead developer I was responsible for the future development of the product in terms of features and quality. Some features of nevisAuth are identity federation, security token issuing and

API authorization.

Salzburg Research

Period July 2008 - December 2011

Position Software Developer & Junior Researcher

Field of Research Knowledge & Media Technology

Projects Knowledge in a Wiki (KiWi) - A framework for social semantic media

applications.

iMedication - An intelligent warning system for adverse drug events.

Skills & Interests

Languages

Nautral German (native), English (fluent)

Development

Languages Profound knowledge in Java.

Good knowledge in JavaScript and TypeScript

Familiar with C++, C, Python, Bash, but not using it on a daily basis.

Recently started learning Go.

Frameworks Play 2.x, JEE, Angular JS 1.x and 2.x, Android, ionic framework

Principles I care about clean software architecture and apply software contracts to pre-

vent coding errors.

Technologies

Protocols Open ID Connect, OAuth 2.0, SAML 2.0, WS-Federation, WS-Trust, WebID,

FIDO UAF, Digital ID

Operating Systems Gentoo Linux, Fedora Linux

Personal Interest

Identity and Access Management, Software Security and Privacy.

Compiler Construction and Memory Management.

Semantic Web, Knowledge Representation and Machine Learning.

Entrepreneurship.

Effective Altruism: Using reason and evidence to determine the most effective ways to improve the world.

Awards

June 2009

March 2016	Participated in the Google Code Jam 2016 for Women coding contest and
	won a ticket and travel stipend to the Google I/O 2016.
April 2013	2nd prize at the HackEd 2.0 Hackathon organised by Facebook and Bill $\&$
	Melinda Gates Foundation.
April 2011	Google Anita Borg Memorial (EMEA) scholarship finalist.
June 2009	Best graduate of Information Technology & Systems Management, University
	of Applied Sciences Salzburg,
	Nominated for best graduate of University of Applied Sciences Salzburg.

Best Demo Award at ESWC 2009 (http://www.kiwi-project.eu).